Guide to the Ben Morea and Aldo Tambellini Papers TAM.530
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Ben Morea and Aldo Tambellini Art Papers
1961-2010
1961-1973
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tambellini, Aldo
Blechman, Max
Morea, Ben
TAM.530
1.5 Linear Feet (4 Boxes; box 4 is an oversized flat box, 20.5 x 16.5 x 3)
Painter Ben Morea, and artist and sculptor Aldo Tambellini were both anarchists active in the artistic and political counterculture in New York City in the 1960s and 1970s. Aldo Tambellini edited and published a newsletter called The Screw with its slogan "Artists in an Anonymous Generation Arise." In 1966 Ben Morea and the poet Dan Georgakas founded a Dada-influenced art group called Black Mask. In May 1968, Black Mask changed its name to Up Against the Wall Motherfuckers. The Motherfuckers (often referred to as simply "the Motherfuckers", or UAW/MF) were an anarchist affinity group based in New York City's Lower East Side. They contributed to New York City's counterculture by setting up crash pads, serving free food, starting a free store, and helping radicals connect with doctors and lawyers. They used direct action to stage various political-artistic events and demonstrations, and are thought to have inspired members of the Weather Underground and the Yippies. This collection contains clippings, fliers, graphic art, periodicals, posters, photographs, programs and other printed ephemera that document Morea and Tambellini's activities both during and before the founding of Black Mask, and the activity of the Motherfuckers. There is also correspondence and other material relating to the Situationist International, several annotated issues of the Rebel Worker (Industrial Workers of the World), and correspondence and other materials created or collected by donor Max Blechman that also pertain to anarchism and its relationship to the arts.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Max Blechman in 2010. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 2010.028 and 2010.089.
Arrangement
Organized into eight series: I, Aldo Tambelini and Ben Morea in the pre-Black Mask Period; II, Black Mask, 1966-1968; II, Up Against the Wall Motherfucker, 1968-1971; IV, Publications of groups in NY and London connected or relevant to Ben Morea and the Up Against the Wall Motherfucker "affinity groups," 1968-1971; V, Situationist International Correspondence; VI, Rebel Worker (Annotated Issues); VII, Max Blechman: Other Anarchy Related Materials; VIII, Oversize Materials.
Each series is arranged alphabetically, except for series V and VI, which are arranged chronologically.
Historical/Biographical Note
Painter Ben Morea, and artist and sculptor Aldo Tambellini were both anarchists active in the artistic and political counterculture in New York City in the 1960s and 1970s. Aldo Tambellini edited and published a newsletter called The Screw with its slogan "Artists in an Anonymous Generation Arise." In 1966 Ben Morea and the poet Dan Georgakas founded a Dada-influenced art group called Black Mask along with elements of another group called Angry Arts. Black Mask produced a broadside of the same name and declared that revolutionary art should be "an integral part of life, as in primitive society, and not an appendage to wealth." In May 1968, Black Mask changed its name and went underground. Their new name, Up Against the Wall Motherfuckers, came from a poem by Amiri Baraka. Often referred to as simply "the Motherfuckers", or UAW/MF, they were an anarchist affinity group based in New York City's Lower East Side. They contributed to New York City's counterculture by setting up crash pads, serving free food, starting a free store, and helping radicals connect with doctors and lawyers. This "street gang with analysis" was known for its direct actions in the fields of politics and the arts, and is said to have inspired members of the Weather Underground and the Yippies.They were opposed to and resisted on principle any attempt to impose order on the political demonstrations they participated in. Among other things, the Motherfuckers instigated brawls with Maoist groups such as the Progressive Labor Party.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains clippings, fliers, graphic art, periodicals, posters, photographs, programs and other printed ephemera that document Morea and Tambellini's activities both during and before the founding of Black Mask, and the activity of the Motherfuckers. There is also correspondence and other material relating to the Situationist International, several annotated issues of the Rebel Worker (Industrial Workers of the World), and correspondence and other materials created or collected by donor Max Blechman that also pertain to anarchism and its relationship to the arts.
Lower East Side (New York, N.Y.) |x Intellectual life.; Art |x Political aspects |z New York (State) |z New York.; Lower East Side (New York, N.Y.) -- Art.; Graphic arts; Posters.; Political satire, American.; Clippings (information artifacts); Rock music |x Political aspects; High school students |x Political activity |z New York (State) |z New York.; Anarchists |z New York (State) |z New York.; Student movements -- United States.; Correspondence.; Photographs.; Black Zero; Black Mask (Group of artists); Blechman, Max; Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts; Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.). Film Library; Fillmore East (New York, N.Y.); Graham, Bill, 1931-1991; Internationale situationniste; Bookchin, Murray, 1921-2006; Blechman, Max; Up Against the Wall Motherfuckers (Gang); Students for a Democratic Society (U.S.)
- Series I: Aldo Tambellini and Ben Morea in the pre-Black Mask Period, 1961-1973 (bulk 1962-1965; 1962-1965
  Scope and Content Note
  This series contains fliers, programs and other printed ephemera and photographs documenting the countercultural artistic endeavors, principally of Aldo Tambellini (there is also a biographical sketch) in the early-mid 1960s. Undertakings documented include the Black Gate Theatre, the arts project "Black Zero," "The Bridge," a downtown performance venue on St. Marks Place, fliers and a statement of purpose for "The Center" (another arts project), movie and gallery openings. The photographs includ images of Tambellini and his paintings and sculpture.
  - Arts Canada #113 (Devoted to the Theme of "Black"), Oct 1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Beck, Julian and Judith Malina in an Open Discussion: Revolution as an Alternative ("Center" flier featuring a photograph of a street kid in front of an Aldo Tambellini sculpture), ca. 1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Black Gate Theatre (2 photographs): Entrance (announcing Underground Cinema); Lobby (seated Kusuma Joe Jones), ca 1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Black 2 fliers for a "Centrefugue Event" at "The Bridge" featuring Morea, Tambellini, et al., ca 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Black Zero: "Expanded Cinema" at the Bridge (4 St. Mark's Pl.) "For Immediate Release", Nov 23, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Black Zero: Fliers (with sperm graphic), Program for Bridge Theater, Dec 15-16, 1965 (Featuring works of Ben Morea, Aldo Tambellini, Ron Hahne, Bill Dixon, Alan Silva, Calvin C. Hernton) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Black Zero: Photograph (woman seated in front of poster "Aldo Tambellini: Intermedia, Electromedia, Theater and Film"), undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bridge Theater Program Featuring Weegee Film Festival, the Fugs, etc., ca 1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The "Center" Flier, with a Calendar of Events ("The Center is an idea for the future, the artist must once again become the vision, we are the primitives of a new era."), ca 1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Center" Flier: Statement of Purpose with the Center Logo (Black circle with one black dot in the center), ca 1963-ca 1964 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Center" Flier: "Subscribe for the Creative Mind to Find Physical Space to Exchange Ideas", ca. 1963 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Expanded Cinema chapter, "Technoanarchy: The Open Empire", undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Group Center article by David Bourdon, Village Voice (photograph of original), Jan 14, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Morea, Ben: Xerox of Photograph, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Painted Black, Pen Sketch, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Photograph, Aldo Tambellini's "Center" Group (Ben Morea, Ron Hahne, Aldo Tambellini, and three unidentified members), 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Photograph of El Diaro de Nueva York, front page with a photograph of Aldo Tambellini, caption about Tambellini's costume creations, Jul 13, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Photoprint Strips: A.M. Sachs Gallery, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Poster for opening of Centrefugues (A series of events in the Arts featuring the work of Jackie Cassen, Jeriann Hilderley, Eileen Larue, Aldo Tambellini, Peter Martinez, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Quantum II Press Release for A.M. Sachs Gallery (Including an explanation of the event and biographies of the participating artists), Jan 5, 196? (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "Rebellion in Art Form-Tambellini's "Black 2" (New York Herald Tribune, photoprint), Jun 13, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "The Screw card, signed by Tambellini, Reads: You are cordially invited to witness the event of the screw, in which a highly significant award will be presented to the Museum of Modern Art...[yellow cardboard 6x8], Jul 12, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Sleeps with His Work, Fights Critics: Sculptor [Aldo Tambellini] Hunts Junk for Fierce Forms by Don Ross (New York Herald Tribune Clipping; Includes a photograph of Tambellini in his studio at 217 East 2nd St., with odd figure he cast), Nov 9, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Tambellini, Aldo (biographical flier), 1967 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Tambellini, Aldo: Biographical Listing in Tamburine/919, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Tambellini film/electromedia performance/television creations list (1965-1980; annotated by Tambellini, 4pp., undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - "Underground" Benefit Bash Flier for "The Bridge" Performances (Including Tambellini's Black Zero and "Light," a film by Ben Morea, ca 1965 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Views and Comments of the Libertarian League no. 46 [cover by Dick Tyler], Spring 1964 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - "Zero" (selections re; from Art and the Future by Douglas Davis, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Series II: Black Mask, 1966-1969
  This small series (1966-1969) includes fliers from the group's 1966 symbolic attempt to close the Museum of Modern Art, and a picture of the Black Mask group, selected poetry and essays, fliers from the 1967 "Levitate the Pentagon" anti-war demonstration, and a single issue of Ikon that includes pictures of the Black Mask group.
  - Black Mask Circular "The Assault against the Black Community...", Jun 23, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Black Mask in WIN magazine (photocopies), 1967 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Flier: "For Immediate Release: ON Monday October 10 [1966] at 12:30pm we will close the Museum of Modern Art. This Symbolic action is taken at a time when America is on a path of total destruction, and signals the opening of another front in the worldwide struggle against suppression. We seek a total revolution, cultural as well as social and political---LET THE STRUGGLE BEGIN." Signed Black Mask. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Flier "Museum Closed": recto, in oversize bold letters: MUSEUM CLOSED; verso: "A new spirit is rising. Like the street of Watts we burn with revolution. We assault your Gods--We sing of your death. Destroy the Museums--our struggle cannot be hung on walls. Let the past fall under the blows of revolt. The guerilla, the blacks, the men of the future, we are at your heels...[etc.]" Signed Black Mask: Ben Morea, Ron Hahne, Everett Shapiro., 1966 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Ikon (#7 Jan-Feb 1969) includes picture of Black Mask Group (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Pentagon Demo fliers, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Selected Essays and Poetry, some by Black Mask, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - "Whirlpool" [flier], undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Your Government Has Fallen (Flier issued by Black Mask), undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Series III: Up Against the Wall Motherfucker, ca. 1967-1970
  This series (1967-1970) contains printed ephemera (much of graphic interest), including fliers, clippings, leaflets, press releases, newsletters, and several photographs. There are files on the UAW/MF campaign to get Bill Graham and the Fillmore East to hold free concerts, on an action to bring garbage to Lincoln Center, files on student movements, including the 1968 occupation of Columbia University, various critiques of education, a single issue of Cerberus (NYU), a typescript by Ben Morea "The Issue Is not the Issue," materials critical of the Old and New Lefts, and a sexually graphic flier "Elecctions are Obscene."
  - ACID (Action Committee for Immediate Defense), undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Armed Love/Love Armed...[flier with graphic of Geronimo], undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Cerberus (vol 1, no. 9) New York University (2 l.), undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Clippings, Miscellaneous, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Columbia University Uprising: 3 fliers, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - "Continuum..." [flier, organization?], undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Elections are Obscene [sexually graphic flier by the Berkeley Commune], 1968 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - From the Book of the Motherfucker [Flier with Comic Strip in Medieval style], undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Fuck Alienated social Science, Fuck Boredom (students of Life), Mar 14, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Graham, Bill; Fillmore East/West; "Free Theatre", 1968, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Hippies Launch Spring Offensive" UAWMF Flier, undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - International Werewolf Conspiracy Flier "You must destroy the student in you", undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Long Live the King, or the First Fuck of John Harvard (signed "appr. les engages), ca. 1968 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Morea, Ben "The Issue os Not the Issue", 1968 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Motherfuckers (pp. 311-3) Year of the Barricades / David Caute, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Original Fliers Concerning Huey Newton's Arrest, titled "Life in Destruction", undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Open Press (flier, East Side Service Organization), ca 1967-ca 1970 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Photographs (10) and negatives: Made by Newsreel Films from the film realized on the occasion of the Lincoln Center Action, Feb 1968 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - The Remnants of the Anti War Movement Gather for Yet Another March" [flier], undated (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - "Survival is not Enough" [flier], undated (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - "This is the Last Act of Masturbation: Let the Fucking Begin," Obscene Anarchist International, ca. 1968 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Up Against the Wall Theatre, undated (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - We Propose a Cultural Exchange (Assemble to collect garbage then march to Lincoln Center), Feb 12, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Up Against the Wall Motherfucker Magazine, 1968 (Box Shared Tamiment XOS003, Folder 1, Box 1, Folder 62)
- Series IV: Publications of groups in NY and London connected or relevant to Ben Morea and Up Against the Wall Motherfucker., 1965-1968, 1992; 1965-1968
  This series contains publications of groups in NY and London connected or relevant to Ben Morea and Up Against the Wall Motherfucker, including cartoonns, clippings, manifestos, pamphlets and other ephemera, including several related to New York City public school student movements, and a typescript, "Root and Branch: A Radical Sixties Odyssey," by Jonathan Leake (91 pp)
  - Address to New York City Public School Students (4pp comic book;New York Section, SI), Nov 12, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - "Affinity Groups" [leaflet, 4pp], undated (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Anarchos #1, Feb 1968 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Cartoon "Grain Assault" (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Collection of Oversize cartoons,...rejected by the Committee of Public Safety...L.S.E...Signed King Mob / The Black Hand Gang, undated (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Comment: The Newest School Buildings are Indistinguishable from the Newest Prison or the Newest Industrial Complexes, Sep 22, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Leake, Jonathan, Notes on cardboard, undated (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Leake, Jonathan; Root and Branch: A Radical Sixties Odyssey (ts. 91 pp), 1992 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Lewin, Roland: Erich Muehsam, 1879-1934, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Lifechants/Songs of Revolution, 1967? (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Mattafesto (from), undated (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - New York Federation of Anarchists (641 East 9th Street): The Legacy of Domination (2 pp.), undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Provisional Committee to Reconstitute the First International (flier), undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Resurgence", May 25, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Thutch 666/Jonathan Leake, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Untitled Critique (#.) re: Women's Liberation, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Watts 1965...[leaflet], undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - We Are All Undesirables: A Little Treatise on Dying [flier], 1968 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Winter Solstice Saturday December 21 [graphic flier; San Francisco], ca 1968 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Series V: Situationist International Correspondence, Documents, History, 1967-1974
  This series contains photocopies of correspondence of the Situationist International (SI), in English and French, including letters from SI leader Guy DeBord, and one letter addressed to American anarchist Murray Bookchin; writings by members of the SI, and writings about the history of the SI.
  - Situationist Correspondence (New york: "Dear Murray [Bookchin];" 1 letter, unsigned), Sep 12, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Situationist Correspondence (London, Paris; in French and English), Nov 25, 1962-Nov 28, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Situationist Correspondence (London, Paris; in French and English), Dec 1967 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - A Field Study in the Dwindling Force of Cognition, where It is the Least Expected: A Critique of the Situationist International as Revolutionary Organization by Robert Chasse and Bruce Ellwell (46 pp.), Feb/Mar 1970 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Gray, Christopher; The Incomplete Work of the Situationist International (apparently selected portions, including a list of members), 1974 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Situationist "Point of Clarification", undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Situationist International: Photocopies of Several Sections of a [published?] Typescript [title not given] 46 pp [possibly complete but lacking title page], undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Series VI: Rebel Worker (Annotated Issues), 1964-1966
  This series contains several annotated issues of the Rebel Worker, the publication of the Industrial Workers of the World, a syndicalist group with anarchist influences.
  - Rebel Worker: Dear Max [Blechman] letter from Franklin [Rosemont], 7/27/1993; Rebel Worker Pamphlets, 1964-1966, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Rebel Worker (#1; 1A), undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Rebel Worker (#3), undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Rebel Worker (#4), 1965 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Rebel Worker (#5), undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Rebel Worker (#6), undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Rebel Worker (#7), undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Series VII: Max Blechman: Other Anarchy Related Materials, 1968-2010
  This series contains correspondence, including on various aspects of anarchism, a notebook by Ben Morea describing the events and people (Aldo Tambellini in particular) covered in series I through V, materials on the anarchist/punk music scence in Great Britain, a memo regarding Murray Bookchin, a single issue of HEAD, and doodles.
  - Blechman, Max: Correspondence, 1992-1996 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Communes: Reprints, Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Doodles, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - The End of Music (Glasgsow): Includes "The Revolution of Everyday Alienation," "Rebel Music and State Morality," usic All Day Helps You Work and Play.", ca. 1968 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - HEAD (Healthier Environmental Attitudes Desired), Sep 1968 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Morea, Ben: Notebook: Black Mask / UAWMF/King Mob/ S.I., ca. 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Radcliffe, Charles: Memo re Murray Bookchin, covering ca. 1966-1970, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Series VIII: Oversize Materials, 1962-1969
  This series contains oversized clippings, periodicals and posters separated from series one through four, and arranged in four corresponding subseries.
  - A. Aldo Tambellini and Ben Morea in the pre-Black Mask Period
    - The Bridge Presents "Outfall" Poster, Sep 1965 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Beck, Julian & Judith Malina in an open discussion: "Revolution as an Alternative." "Center" flyer featuring a photograph of a street kid in front of an Aldo Tambellini sculpture., Ca. 1964 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Village Voice "Theater Journal" article with photos covering "OUTFALL" in which a machine created by Ben Morea and Aldo Tambellini were featured., September 30 1965 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Village Voice, "Theater Journal", re Black Zero/Tambellini, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 3A)
    - Evo interview prints, with "Black Sperm" photo portrait of Aldo Tambellini. Questions by Lil Picard addressed to Aldo Tambellini, titled: "Art Child is Black.", Ca. Nov 1967-ca, Dec 1967 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - The Center [poster, 11.5 x 17] re: showing of Quantum 1 at the Noah Goldowsky Gallery featuring Charles Mingus, Louise Bourgeois, Aldo Tambellini, Benn Morea, Ron Hahne, Ad Reinhardt, et. al., ca. 1965 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Quantum exhibits: Photograph (oversized) of Tambellini's works, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Quantum 2: Poster (11.5" x 17") of Group Center and Group Zero's showing of at Sachs Gallery and Noah Goldowsky Gallery. Featuring Peter Agostini, Louise Bourgeois, Ilise Greenstein, Ron Hahne, Chuck Hinman, Charles Mingus, Benn Morea, Aldo Tambellini, et. al., 1965 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - New York Post clipping (Wednesday June 12, 1963) with a piece on Aldo Tambellini by Sally Hammond titled "Downtown Artists Have a Coming Out." (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - The Screw: A Newsletter of Social Consciousness (Issues 1-5; photocopies). The first issue (March/April 1962) announces: "The artist is dying a controlled death." (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - B. Black Mask
    - Black Mask [tabloid paper], issues 2 and 9 [photocopies], 1966, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - C. Up Against the Wall Motherfucker
    - Up Against the Wall Motherfucker oversize poster (around 16" x 24") of fiery skeleton with the International Werewolf Conspiracy logo. (A Rat centerfold.), undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - ACID (Action Committee for Immediate Defense) Up Against the Wall Motherfucker poster/comic titled "Agent of Acid: Lower East Side Defense.", undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Page in a complete issue of The Rat (January 24-30, 1969, p. 5): on Ben Morea's acquittal after a four-day trial in Boston on two counts of assault and battery with a deadly weapon. (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Journal of The Resistance (October 1968): Page in a complete issue of with an article by Ben Morea, "The Issue Is Not the Issue" which defines "the revolutionary project as the total destruction of dominant bourgeois reality." The article is published following an editorial note drafted by the "Ben Morea Defense Fund" calling for funds. (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - "Armed Love" Up Against the Wall Motherfucker poster: "TO LIVE ONE MUST LOVE, TO LOVE ONE MUST SURVIVE, TO SURVIVE ONE MUST FIGHT!", undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - D. Publications of groups in NY and London connected or relevant to Ben Morea and the Up Against the Wall Motherfucker "affinity groups,"
    - Action (Paris: Realise au Service des Comittes D'Action), Oct 1968 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Broadside "High School Strike" "Rally Sunday October 27, Washington Square Park", undated (Box 4, Folder 17)